Raj Shekhawat

Fort Worth, Texas, United States



rishirajsshekhawat@gmail.com



+14696383337



linkedin.com/in/raj-shekhawat

Summary

I identify myself as a WordPress specialist and SEO expert because, over the course of my career, I have garnered

profound hands-on Frontend, back-end development, Web Design, Web Development, SEO, and UIUX experience that helps me in providing 360-degree WordPress solutions to your business requirements.

Having 11 years of Experience with Website designing and development, online Marketplace, e-commerce design, development using platforms such as WordPress, wooCommerce eCommerce (WordPress plugin), WordPress plugin Development, Laravel, Shopify, Squarespace, Wix, SEO, and many other CMS.

I have Knowledge of:

HTML, CSS, Jquery, Angular JS, Trello, Speed optimization, Google Page Speed Optimization, WordPress, WooCommerce, PHP, Industry Knowledge, SEO, Web Development, Web Design, Security, Search Engine Optimization (SEO), Server Administration, Web Services, Front-end Development, Software Project Management, Database Design, Tools & Technologies, Laravel, HTML, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), HTML5, AngularJS, jQuery, RESTful WebServices, REST APIs, Wix Website Builder, Google Search Console, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), PhpMyAdmin, JSON, AJAX, JavaScript, JavaScript Frameworks, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Jira, QuickBooks, MySQL, GitHub, Shopify, Wix,

Other Skills:

On-Page SEO, Off-Page SEO, Website Building, Website Updating, Web Services API, API Development, Google API, Google Maps API, Style Sheets, Full-Stack Development, Back-End Web Development, Front-end Design, Strong Analytical Skills, Adaptability / Multitasking, Consumers & Market Research, Management Experience, WordPress developer specializing in custom themes and plugins. I've worked as a full-time developer for an established marketing and web design company with hundreds of clients. This gave me a strong background in everything from building custom themes from scratch to modifying and reworking existing themes, complex project development and handling, designing and developing tools and plugins, building and launching web applications, and troubleshooting bugs.

I'm comfortable with a wide range of websites, including personal blogs, corporate websites, and large e-commerce stores. I love to code, but I'm also passionate about good design and intuitive user experience and bring that to everything I do.

Thanks,

Regards,

Rishi.

Experience

Senior WordPress PHP Developer and SEO Team Leader

AT&T Software LLC

Aug 2015 - Present (6 years 3 months +)

A Dallas, Texas, United States Website Company where I worked as a senior WordPress developer and SEO Team Leader. My time at AT&T Software LLC was spent working on different aspects of web development, that included:

- Building SaaS applications in agile environments (Scrum, Kanban). Experience involves building scalable web apps using frameworks like WordPress and Laravel.
- Apart from implementing responsive frontend and U/IUX solutions, worked with page builders like Elementor/bakery
- Developed client websites and applications based on design hand off-provided by lead designers
- Provided troubleshooting and technical support for clients and internal team members for launched projects and other IT-related issues such as DNS, hosting, email, and desktop configuration
- Strategized with clients and management team to help provide the best tech strategies and stacks for projects
- Explored new tools like Rackstation for management of files and assets utilized on client sites and Function Point for project management and hours tracking
- SEO: Developing a detailed project plan and monitor the progress of SEO. Make decisions about the day-to-day operation of the team members, including management of work assignments by them. I oversee the research of SEO to help the digital marketing team run effective campaigns, as well as to optimize the company's website, social media pages, and other content efforts.

Wordpress Developer

Webrock Media Private Limited

Jan 2012 - Feb 2015 (3 years 2 months)

The hallmark of my career was working full-time Wordpress Developer at Webrock Media Private Limited, the company behind the renowned theme and visual page builder 'Divi'. As a WordPress Engineer, I was responsible for:

- · Working on various aspects of SDLC regarding a new proprietary theme
- Create and Optimizing plugin that dealt with migrations and removed issues caused due to subsequent WordPress updates
- Implementing better UIUX for Divi re-vamp by writing reduced CSS and making optimized bundles
- · Enabled dark mode feature and dynamic font sizes for accessibility
- Re-architecture of image rendering performance of Divi and other website builders
- Mentored three developer interns

Front End Designer & Search Engine Optimization

Next Big Technology (NBT)

Apr 2010 - Dec 2011 (1 year 9 months)

At Next Big Technology (NBT), I embarked on a journey to become a WordPress Developer. Although I was hired as a junior frontend designer, SEO to make custom UIUX, HTML to the WordPress sites, I quickly

learned about various tools of the trade and taught myself PHP. I consolidated my templating skills by learning about Bootstrap, LESS, and Sass, which were the hottest trend of that time.

The agency had multiple web development clients and I worked with a team that was assigned on CMS-based front-end designing projects. My team included Graphic designers and a Frontend developer,

My day-to-day tasks included:

- Front End Designer
- Search Engine Optimization

- Reviewing site optimization
- Theme Implementation and customization
- Plug-in implementation and customization
- Custom UIUX tweaks
- WordPress site development
- E-commerce store development using WooCommerce
- Setting up databases and integrating REST APIs
- Followed agile methodology and conducted sprint plans and scrum meetings for the management of the tasks

Education



JNTUH College of Engineering Hyderabad

Master of Computer Applications - MCA, Computer Science Jan 2010 - Jul 2013

Skills

WordPress • WooCommerce • PHP • Laravel • SEO • On-Page SEO • Off-Page SEO • HTML Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
HTML5